Summary_

Computer Science & Engineering student recognized by GitHub as a Campus Expert. Interested in studying algorithms & data structures and have completed multiple certifications and courses for the same. Experienced in backend development and server management. Enjoy working in a team setup, presently leading a community of 2500+ student on campus as general secretary of the CS club. Love learning new skills and implementing them to solve problems.

Work Experience

GitHub Education Remote

GITHUB CAMPUS EXPERT

Sep. 2018 - Present

· Selected by GitHub from a global application pool as a Campus Expert on the basis of proficiency in Git and work towards community building.

- Conducted multiple workshops and taught Git to 300+ students.
- Trained by GitHub in public speaking, technical writing, community leadership and software development skills.

IECSE Manipal(Official Computer Science Club of MIT, Manipal)

Manipal, India

GENERAL SECRETARY

Jul. 2018 - Present

- Leading and managing a community of over 2500 students on campus.
- · Gave talks and conducted workshops on Introduction to web development, Introduction to APIs, API development using Flask, Database management, Server management & Security alongside working on development projects with the community and conducting competitions.

Nebula Infomatique New Delhi, India

WEB ADMIN

May. 2017 - Jul. 2017

- Developed company website (http://nebulainfomatique.com) along with setting up mail servers and providing tech support and training.
- The website has a Google speed score of 97(Mobile) & 100(Desktop) while the competitor's website has a score of 5(Mobile) & 63(Desktop).

Projects & Skills

DAMN - SSH Keys Distribution and Management Network

SKILLS: GOLANG, GIT, SERVER MANAGEMENT, SHELL SCRIPTING, OAUTH, API DEVELOPMENT, ORM

- · Worked with a team of 2 members to develop a web application for securely requesting, granting and revoking access to servers by managing the SSH keys of all node servers through one single central server.
- · Developed the complete backend for the web app using Golang while working with various APIs, OAuth protocol, shell scripting, database management and various other technologies.

Plauto - Database Systems Project

SKILLS: SQL, DATABASE MANAGEMENT, PYTHON(FLASK), HTML, CSS, GIT

- · Worked with a team of 3 members to develop a web app to automate parking lot management as a project for Database System course.
- · Undertook the development of the backend using Flask, frontend using HTML & CSS and integration of the web app with the database.

FIFAWC - CLI App

SKILLS: GOLANG, BASH, API INTEGRATION

• Developed a Command Line Interface (CLI) app using Golang and web APIs to track the FIFA World Cup 2018 by getting live scores, fixtures, team details and other statistics right from the terminal.

Education

Manipal Institute of Technology

Manipal, India

B.Tech. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug. 2016 - Exp. Jul. 2020

 CGPA: 8.65(Scale of 10.0). **Mount Carmel School**

New Delhi, India

HIGH AND SECONDARY SCHOOL EDUCATION

2002 - 2016

• CBSE 12th class: 93.5% and CBSE 10th class: 9.4 CGPA(Scale of 10.0).

Relevant Courses & Certifications

Algorithmic Toolbox, Data Structures, Algorithms on Graphs, Algorithms on Strings by University of California San Diego & National Research University Higher School of Economics on Coursera and Algorithms, Database Management System, Computer Networks, Data Communication, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture by Manipal Institute of Technology as per B.Tech. curriculum.

NISHCHAY PARASHAR FEBRUARY, 2019